Guide to the Tamar Carroll Oral Histories on Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM!) OH.066
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- WHAM! Group Interview, 2005-12-16; cuid34425 (Box Shared Access Audio 2, Cd OH-66-012, Box 1, Cd TW_OH_066_5, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_66_ER_11)
  Charles K. Alexander II is labor leader, socialist, feminist, and women's rights activist. He is a former member of Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM!), Freedom Socialist Party, Radical Women, Reproductive Rights Coalition. In the 1980s, he was a shop steward in an unspecified labor union at New York University.
  Mark Jacquinot is a lawyer and former member of WHAM!. Jacquinot lived in Iowa in the 1970s and was a founder and secretary-treasurer of Crisis in Iowa, a member of the Ames Pro-Choice Coalition, before moving to Buffalo, NY in 1984 to attend law school and moving to New York City in 1988.
  Mary Anne Staniszewski is an art and cultural historian, and former member of WHAM! and the Reproductive Rights Coalition. She was a member of the media wing of WHAM!.
  This interview was conducted by Tamar Carroll at an unspecified location on December 16, 2005. The interview was recorded on video. Charles K. Alexander II, Mark Jacquinot, and Mary Anne Staniszewski discuss their backgrounds, what drew them to Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM!), and their experiences in WHAM!. All three were involved in the Reproductive Rights Coalition (RRC) and were members of WHAM! from its beginning. Alexander and Staniszewski describe the beginnings of WHAM! as the direct action committee of RRC and how it eventually separated to become its own organization. They discuss the differences between the two organizations and their preference for WHAM! and its philosophy. Jacquinot and Alexander discuss their work in abortion clinic defense and protests in New York City in the 1980s and 1990s.
- WHAM! Reunion, 2005-10-15; cuid34426 (Box Shared Access Audio 2, Cd OH-66-013, Box 1, Cd TW_OH_066_6, Box Electronic Records, E-records TW_OH_66_ER_12)
  Historical Note
  The Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM!) Reunion took place at the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives on October 15, 2005. The event included presentations by a panel of former WHAM! members and Tamar Carroll, followed by comments and questions from former WHAM! members in the audience. The panel included Mary Anne Staniszewski, Michele Tepper, Marian Cole, Leslie Wolf, Meryl Levin, and Carroll.
  The Women's Health Action and Mobilization (WHAM!) Reunion was recorded on video on October 15, 2005. The event is opened by former head of Tamiment Michael H. Nash who discusses the relationship between Tamiment and WHAM!, Carroll's dissertation project, and the work of the Tamiment Library. Levin shares a slideshow of images from WHAM! events and direct actions. Carroll discusses her dissertation topic and her relationship with the former members of WHAM! with whom she conducted oral histories. The bulk of the reunion focuses on the presentations of Staniszewski, Tepper, Cole, Wolf, and Levin who each discuss how they became active in WHAM! and the importance of WHAM!'s work. They focus on what made WHAM! special; the coalitions WHAM! formed with other activist groups, especially ACT-UP and the Reproductive Rights Coalition; and the ways in which WHAM! impacted each of them individually. The remainder of the recording includes people from the audience sharing their experiences with WHAM!.
- WHAM! Action, 1990; cuid34427 (Box 1, Audiocassette OH.066.015)